

Justin Furlotte

MSc Mathematics

I am a graduate student researching mathematical physics (in particular, the Quantum Hall Effect) as a member of the Institute of Applied Mathematics at the University of British Columbia. Other than physics, I also have a strong interest in applied mathematics, including scientific computing, mathematical modelling, and machine learning.

justin.furlotte@gmail.com



(506) 304-7625



GPA: 88%

GPA: 4.0

Vancouver



👿 justin-furlotte.github.io

EDUCATION

MSc - Mathematics University of British Columbia

09/2020 - Present

Awards

 NSERC Canada Graduate Scholarship - Master's (CGS-M).

 Faculty of Graduate Studies Award (x2).

SKILLS

Machine Learning

Python

PyTorch

Scikit-Learn

Pandas

Jupyter

Julia

MATLAB

SQL

LaTeX

B.Sc (Honours) - Mathematics-Physics

University of New Brunswick

09/2015 - 12/2019

Awards

- NSERC Experience Award (2018).
- The Arthur and Sandra Irving Primrose Scholarship (2015-2019).
- Dr. Ker-Ping Lee Memorial Scholarship (2019).
- Older awards available upon request.

PROJECTS & PUBLICATIONS

Geophysical Inversion with Deep Neural Networks

 Variational autoencoder in PyTorch, combined with UBC geophysics lab's inversion software, to model subsurface density.

Variational Autoencoder Lecture

• Sample lecture & assignment created for UBC's CPSC 540 (Advanced Machine Learning) course.

Ensemble ML xG Model

- Created an expected goals model to detect outlier goal scoring seasons of NHL players.
- Significant preprocessing of data from moneypuck.com.
- Created Plotly/Dash dashboard app, deployed with Heroku.

Master's Thesis - The Quantum Hall Effect

- Proving bulk-edge correspondence in interacting lattice systems.
- Uses mathematical tools such as functional analysis, spectral theory, and operator algebras.

Vector-Quantized Naïve Bayes

- Full from-scratch implementation in Julia.
- Modification of ordinary naïve Bayes which adds a latent variable using unsupervised classification.

Publication with C-Therm Technologies

• M. Emanuel, M. Bhouri, J. Furlotte, D. Groulx, J. Maassen: Temperature Fields Generated by a Circular Heat Source (CHS) in an Infinite Isotropic Medium: Treatment of Contact Resistances with Application to Thin Films, International Journal of Heat and Mass Transfer 137:677-689 (April 2019).

Other Projects & Where to View

 These projects and more can be browsed in greater detail on my personal website, https://justinfurlotte.github.io.

RECENT WORK EXPERIENCE

R&D Scientist

C-Therm Technologies

06/2017 - 08/2020 Achievements/Tasks

Fredericton, NB, Canada

• Designed and implemented machine learning/regression algorithms in Python to extract thermal material properties from experimental curves.

- Created the "Flex TPS" regression algorithm, one of C-Therm's core
- products which retails for \$9,100.
- Performed computational physics research on cutting-edge technologies, resulting in a publication.

Head Teaching Assistant University of British Columbia

09/2020 - 04/2022

MATH 110 (Introduction to Differential Calculus); MATH 307 (Applied Linear Algebra) Achievements/Tasks

- Leader of all TAs for UBC's Differential Calculus course.
- Created weekly teaching plans, problem sets, and solutions for graduate TAs.
- High reviews from student evaluation surveys for ability to explain complex mathematical concepts in simple language.